都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore, 呼び出す[よびだす]:to summon/to call (e.g. phone)|to invoke (e.g. subroutine), 子供[こども]:child/children
（ヤサコ）都市伝説によると
ミチコさんを呼び出した子供は―
According to urban legend,
kids who call out to Miss Michiko are sent to the "other side".
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 連れる[つれる]:to lead/to take (a person), しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
あっちに
連れてゆかれてしまうそうです
（サッチー）
ボク サッチー ヨロシクネ
Me Satchii.
Nice to meet ya!
しゃべる:to talk/to chat/to chatter
しゃべった！
（フミエ）こっちよ
It spoke?
Follow me!
Coil Cyberinvestigation
Agency
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
あれは
一体なんなの？
What on earth was that?!
あれがサッチーよ
That was Satchii!
撃つ[うつ]:to shoot (at)|to attack/to defeat, メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 壊す[こわす]:to break|to wreck|to break (a bill, etc.)
撃たれたら
メガネ壊されるのよ
If it hits us, our glasses will shatter!
（サッチー）ボク サッチー
Me Satchii.
鳥居[とりい]:torii/Shinto shrine archway, どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives)
鳥居は？　鳥居はどっち？
The torii... Where's the torii?!
A torii is the gate at the entrance of a Shinto shrine; it separates the material world from the spiritual.
こっちよ
Over here!
This way.
えーっと:let me see/well/errr ..., 信号[しんごう]:signal/signalling|traffic light
えーっと 信号 信号…
The light, the light...
あっ 来た！
っと… これだ！
Here it is!
（サッチー）ボク サッチー
ボク サッチー…
Me Satchii.
Me Satchii...
（サッチー）ボク サッチー
ハァ…
反応[はんのう, はんおう]:reaction/response, 残る[のこる]:to remain/to be left
（イサコ）反応がまだ残っている
I'm still getting a weak signal.
通常[つうじょう]:common/general/normal, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 溶ける[とける]:to melt/to thaw/to fuse, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
通常空間では
すぐ溶けてしまうはずなのに…
Strange. It's supposed to fade immediately in normal space.
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 以外[いがい]:with the exception of/excepting, イリーガル:illegal, 生き延びる[いきのびる]:to survive/to live long, 場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho
古い空間以外に
イリーガルが生き延びられる場所…
Where else can an Illegal survive besides an obsolete Space?
ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET
ペットの中だ
Inside a pet!
呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
モジョを呼んだほうがよさそうね
I guess I'd better call the Mojos.
It hurts...
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
Yeah.
（フミエ）はい
Here.
助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|, ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks, 探偵[たんてい]:detective/sleuth/investigator
デンスケを助けてくれてありがとう
探偵さん
Thank you for rescuing Densuke,
Detective.
フミエでいいわ
Call me Fumie.
呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
じゃ 私のことはヤサコって呼んで
Then you can call me Yasako.
（フミエ）ヤサコ？
Yasako?
優しい[やさしい]:tender/kind/gentle, 書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw
優子(ゆうこ)のユウは
優しいって書くの
The "yu" in Yuko can also be read as the "yasa" from "yasashii".
Yasashii means kindhearted and tender.
だから金沢(かなざわ)ではヤサコって
So in Kanazawa they used to call me Yasako.
（フミエ）へえー
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 赤い[あかい]:red|Red (i.e. communist)
ねえ それより
さっきの赤いのどうしたの？
By the way, what happened to that red thing?
神社[じんじゃ]:Shinto shrine, 学校[がっこう]:school, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family
（フミエ）
サッチーは神社とか学校とか
家の中には入ってこないの
Satchii can't enter places such as Shinto shrines, schools or houses.
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
（ヤサコ）
サッチーって 一体なんなの？
What exactly is Satchii?
サーチ:search, マトン:mutton, 略す[りゃくす]:to abbreviate/to omit|to take
本当の名前はサーチマトン
略してサッチー
Its full name is Searchmaton.
Satchii for short.
大黒[だいこく]:god of wealth|monk's wife, 市[いち]:market/fair, 市[し]:city, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 管理[かんり]:control/management (e.g. of a business), 室[しつ]:room|wife (of someone of high rank)|scabbard|, 室[むろ]:greenhouse/icehouse/cellar, 導入[どうにゅう]:introduction/bringing in/leading in, 強力[きょうりょく]:powerful/strong, 強力[ごうりき]:herculean strength/mountain carrier-guide, ウイルス:virus, 駆除[くじょ]:extermination (esp. pests)/expulsion/destruction, ソフト:soft
大黒市(だいこくし)の空間管理室が導入した
強力なウイルス駆除ソフトよ
The Cyberspace Administration introduced it in Daikoku City
as a powerful piece of antivirus software.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), メタタグ:META tag
でも すごくバカだから
メタタグとか―
But he's so stupid that he attacks metatags,
ルール:rule, 違反[いはん]:violation/offense/offence, 違反[いへん]:breaking (a contract, promise, etc.), ちゃめ:playfulness/mischief|brown eyes, アイテム:item
ちょっとルール違反の
おちゃめなアイテムも
playful items slightly against the rules,
見境[みさかい]:distinction/discrimination, 攻撃[こうげき]:attack/strike|criticism
見境なく攻撃してくるのよね
and anything like that without distinction.
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 迷惑[めいわく, べいこく]:trouble/bother/annoyance
ホント迷惑だわ
He's so annoying.
額[がく]:picture (framed)|amount or sum (of money), 額[ひたい]:forehead/brow, 光線[こうせん]:beam/light ray
額から 光線 出すのが―
Shooting beams from your forehead is not what I'd call playful...
ちゃめ:playfulness/mischief|brown eyes, 思える[おもえる]:to seem/to appear likely
それほど
おちゃめとも思えないけどね
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 治療[ちりょう, じりょう]:medical treatment/cure
とにかく早く
デンスケ 治療しましょう
Anyway, let's go heal Densuke quickly.
Okay.
んっ？　どうしたの？
What's wrong?
辺[へん]:area|side|circumstances, 辺[へ, べ]:surrounding area|shore (of the sea)|suffix used as a rough indicator of location, direction, time, etc., 神社[じんじゃ]:Shinto shrine
ねえ この辺って 神社 多いの？
Hey, are there a lot of Shinto shrines around here?
Shrines?
神社[じんじゃ]:Shinto shrine
神社？
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 街[がい]:.. street/.. quarter/.. district, 街[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||, いっぱい:one defeat, いっぱい:amount necessary to fill a container (e.g. cupful, spoonful, etc.)/drink (usu. alcoholic)|full
古い街だから いっぱいあるわ
Well, this is an old town, so there are quite a few.
It's easier to run away from Satchii thanks to them.
おかげ:grace (of God)/benevolence (of Buddha)|assistance, 逃げる[にげる]:to escape/to run away, やすい:cheap/inexpensive|calm, やすい:easy|likely to .../have a tendency to ...
おかげで
サッチーから逃げやすいの
Is there a place with stairs that have lots of torii on them?
鳥居[とりい]:torii/Shinto shrine archway, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), いっぱい:one defeat, いっぱい:amount necessary to fill a container (e.g. cupful, spoonful, etc.)/drink (usu. alcoholic)|full, 並ぶ[ならぶ]:to line up/to stand in a line|to rival, 階段[かいだん]:stairs/stairway/staircase
ねえ 鳥居がすごくいっぱい
並んでる階段って
どこかにない？
辺り[あたり, ほとり]:on the bank of|(in the) neighbourhood|around (Sunday, last year, etc...)|
この辺りで？
Around here?
生まれる[うまれる]:to be born, ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.), 住む[すむ]:to live (of humans)/to reside/to inhabit
私 生まれてから
ずっと住んでるけど知らないな
I've been living here my whole life,
and I've never heard of it.
そう
Is that so...
Okay, let's go.
（フミエ）さっ 行きましょう
Yeah.
The Space is so fragile in this town.
空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, もろい:brittle/fragile/tender-hearted, 街[がい]:.. street/.. quarter/.. district, 街[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||
それにしても空間のもろい街だな
（モジョ）モジョ
Mojo!
Line up!
整列[せいれつ]:standing in a row/forming a line/alignment
（イサコ）整列！
（モジョたち）
モジョ モジョ モジョ モジョ…
Mojo!
Roll call!
点呼[てんこ]:roll-call/muster
点呼！
（モジョたち）
モジョ モジョ モジョ モジョ…
Alright.
鍵穴[かぎあな, カギあな]:keyhole, 見つける[みつける, みっける]:to discover|to locate|to be used to seeing
よし 鍵穴を見つけるんだ
Find the keyhole.
かかる:to span/to bridge/to cross, かかる:to take (a resource, e.g. time or money)|to hang
かかれ！
Move out!
（モジョたち）
モジョ モジョ モジョ…
心当たり[こころあたり]:having in mind/happening to know of/idea
（ヤサコ）心当たりってどこ？
Where do you think we might find it?
薬[くすり]:medicine|efficacious chemical (gunpowder, pesticide, etc.)|(pottery) glaze|, 薬[やく]:dope/narcotics|medication, 売る[うる]:to sell, 所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places, 怪しい[あやしい]:suspicious/dubious|charming
（フミエ）薬を売ってる所よ
ちょっと怪しいけどね
At the medicine shop.
But it's a bit creepy.
Is it that Megashi store again?
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance, 屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||
（ヤサコ）
もしかして またメガシ屋？
Bingo!
当たり[あたり]:hit|success|guess||, メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 駄菓子[だがし]:cheap sweets, 屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||
（フミエ）当たり
メガネの駄菓子屋でメガシ屋
It's called like that because they sell MEGAne, but it's also a daGASHI store.
Megane means glasses in Japanese.
Hold on... A dagashi store?
駄菓子[だがし]:cheap sweets, 屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||
待てよ… 駄菓子屋？
（フミエ）んっ？　どうかしたの？
What's wrong with that?
Mother!
義母[ぎぼ]:mother-in-law|foster mother|step mother
（静江(しずえ)）お義母(かあ)さん！
Why did you put this sign up without asking me first?!
看板[かんばん]:signboard|draw|reputation (of a shop)||, 勝手[かって]:one's own convenience|surroundings|convenience||, 付ける[つける]:to attach|to furnish (a house with)|to wear||
なんで こんな看板
勝手に付けたんです？
So this is what you were hiding from me the last time I came by!
隠す[かくす]:to hide/to conceal
前 来たとき隠してたのは
これだったのね
This is my property!
土地[とち, どおじ]:plot of land/lot|locality, 勝手[かって]:one's own convenience|surroundings|convenience||
（メガばあ）わしの土地じゃ
わしが何しようと勝手じゃ！
I'll do as I please!
Mega-baa!
ださい:uncool/unsophisticated/unfashionable
（フミエ）
メガばあ くっださいな！
Could you sell me some merchandise?
（メガばあ）おっ おお！
フミちゃん 聞いとくれ
Fumie! Come over here!
This devil of a daughter-in-law is pestering me!
鬼嫁[おによめ]:cruel wife/termagant wife/wife from hell, いじめる:to tease/to torment/to persecute
この鬼嫁がいじめるんじゃ！
What are you saying?
恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful
（静江）
何言ってるんですか 恥ずかしい！
You're so embarrassing!
Shut up, you devil of a daughter-in-law!
うるさい:noisy/loud|annoying, 鬼嫁[おによめ]:cruel wife/termagant wife/wife from hell, 訴える[うったえる]:to raise|to appeal to (reason, emotions, etc.)|to complain||
（メガばあ）うるさい！
この鬼嫁めが！　訴えるぞ
I'll call the cops!
Yasako, let me introduce you.
We built the addition, not you!
紹介[しょうかい]:introduction/presentation/referral
ヤサコ 紹介するわ　メガばあよ
She's Mega-baa.
How could you put such a weird sign on it?!
Yasako?
ヤサコ？
引っ越す[ひっこす, ひきこす]:to move (house)/to change residence
だからイヤって言ったのよ
おばばんとこに引っ越すの
This is why I didn't want to move to Granny's place!
The new disposition of the house is of bad luck!
Where did she come from?!
What's wrong?
（フミエ）ねえ どうしたの？
I don't get along well with Granny because she's so cunning.
苦手[にがて]:poor (at)/weak (in)|dislike (of), がめつい:greedy/grasping/predatory
私 おばば苦手なのよ
がめついから
You think so?
そう？
How much does that medicine cost?
薬[くすり]:medicine|efficacious chemical (gunpowder, pesticide, etc.)|(pottery) glaze|, 薬[やく]:dope/narcotics|medication, いくら:how much?/how many?|even, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
ねえ その薬って
いくらくらいするの？
Let me see...
くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
そうねえ 400メタくらいかな
I think it's around 400 meta.
How much is 400 meta?
400メタって？
About four million yen.
大体[だいたい]:outline|general|in the first place, 万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|, 円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
大体 400万円
F-Four million yen?!
万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|, 円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
よ… 400万円？
This medicine is for removing bugs.
取る[とる]:to take|to steal|to eat||, 薬[くすり]:medicine|efficacious chemical (gunpowder, pesticide, etc.)|(pottery) glaze|, 薬[やく]:dope/narcotics|medication, 万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|, 円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
（メガばあ）
これがバグ取り薬 30万円
Three million yen.
Do you have the one from last time?
こないだ:the other day/lately/recently
（フミエ）こないだのは？
（メガばあ）あるよ
Sure.
Download accelerator: two million yen.
ダウンロード:download, 促進剤[そくしんざい]:accelerant/stimulant, 万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|, 円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
（メガばあ）
ダウンロード促進剤 20万円
What about mega-be?
（フミエ）メガビーある？
Megane-beam,
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, ビーム:beam, 秒[びょう]:second (60th min), 万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|, 円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
メガネビーム 10秒 300万円
ten second charge: three million yen.
壁[かべ, へき]:wall|barrier|Chinese "Wall" constellation (one of the 28 mansions), レンガ:brick, 枚[まい]:counter for flat objects (e.g. sheets of paper), 枚[びら, ビラ]:bill/handbill/flier, 万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|, 円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
あっ 壁いるか？
レンガ 10枚 300万円
Do you want a wall?
Brick: three million yen.
Do you have a steel wall?
鉄壁[てっぺき]:iron wall/impregnable fortress, 鉄[かね, かな]:money|metal, 鉄[てつ]:iron (Fe)|strong and hard (as iron)|railway|, 切らす[きらす]:to be out of/to run out of/to be short of
（フミエ）鉄壁は？
（メガばあ）鉄は切らしとる
We're out of stock.
Then I want an accelerator, a mega-be, and...
促進剤[そくしんざい]:accelerant/stimulant
じゃあ 促進剤とメガビーと…
ten brick walls.
レンガ:brick, 枚[まい]:counter for flat objects (e.g. sheets of paper), 枚[びら, ビラ]:bill/handbill/flier, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
それと レンガ10枚ください
6.2 million yen.
万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|, 円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
（メガばあ）620万円
So it's not really four million.
万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|
（ヤサコ）
400万って そういう400万ね
Of course not!
当たり前[あたりまえ]:natural/reasonable|usual
（フミエ）当たり前でしょ
What about the key?
鍵[かぎ, カギ]:key|lock, 鍵[けん]:key (of a piano, etc.), 移す[うつす]:to change|to change the object of one's interest or focus|to spend or take time||
（ヤサコ）鍵は？
（静江）金沢の移してあるわよ
It's the same one we had in Kanazawa.
I'm back.
ただいま:Here I am/I'm home!|presently
ただいま
Come on in.
どうぞ:please/kindly|by all means
どうぞ
A voice key isn't safe nowadays.
今どき[いまどき]:these days/nowadays|at this time (of the day), 音声[おんせい, おんじょう]:voice/(the concept of) sound, 鍵[かぎ, カギ]:key|lock, 鍵[けん]:key (of a piano, etc.), 危ない[あぶない]:dangerous|in danger|uncertain||
今どき 音声鍵だけじゃ危ないわよ
Hello there!
お邪魔[おじゃま]:hindrance/intrusion
（フミエ）お邪魔します
Be my guest.
遠慮[えんりょ]:reserve|declining|forethought
（ヤサコ）遠慮しないで
新築[しんちく]:new building/new construction
（ヤサコ）おおー！
（フミエ）うわっ 新築だ
Oh, it's a brand-new house!
How beautiful! It's so great!
キレイ:pretty/lovely/beautiful, 最高[さいこう]:most/highest|best
キレイ 最高！
If only these cardboard boxes weren't here...
ダンボール:(corrugated) cardboard
このダンボールさえなければ
Yeah.
（フミエ）そうね
（京子(きょうこ)）うわっ…
（ヤサコ）京子
Kyoko!
ウンチ！
Poop!
ウンチ！　ウンチ！
マイブーム:current obsession/current kick/personal obsession, 指さす[ゆびさす]:to point at
マイブームなの
何 見ても指さして“ウンチ”
It's her current obsession.
She says "Poop," whenever she points at something.
ウンチ！
Poop!
ご飯[ごはん]:cooked rice|meal
（静江）はい キョウちゃん
もうすぐご飯ですよ
Hi, Kyo-chan.
Dinner will be ready soon.
（静江）言っちゃダメ！
Don't even say it!
ウイルススキャン:virus, ウイルススキャン:scan
ウイルススキャンは…
The virus scan says...
Densuke
ウイルス:virus, 感染[かんせん]:infection/contagion, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
よかった
ウイルスには感染してないみたい
Good news! You don't appear to be infected by a virus.
Downloading System Restore - Error
修復[しゅうふく, しゅふく]:restoration/repair/mending, 進む[すすむ]:to advance|to precede|to make progress||, 進む[すさむ]:to grow wild/to run to waste
あれ？　修復が進まない
Huh?
The restore isn't working.
促進剤[そくしんざい]:accelerant/stimulant, 貼る[はる]:to stick|to stretch|to form (e.g. ice on a pond)||
促進剤を貼ってみよう
Let's try with the accelerator.
いらっしゃる:to come/to go|is (doing)
いらっしゃい
Welcome.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful
さっきは
恥ずかしいところ見られちゃって
I'm sorry about the mess earlier.
お邪魔[おじゃま]:hindrance/intrusion
お邪魔してまーす
Hello, ma'am.
I'm glad to see you have a new friend.
Downloading System Restore
Connected to C Main
せっかく:stone burial chamber, せっかく:with trouble/at great pains|rare, 友達[ともだち]:friend/companion
（静江）せっかく
お友達になってくれたことだし
夕食[ゆうしょく]:evening meal/dinner, 一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
お夕食 一緒にどうかしら？
Would you like to stay for dinner?
どうぞ:please/kindly|by all means
（ヤサコ）はい どうぞ
Here you go.
いただく:to receive/to get|to eat
（２人）いただきまーす
Itadakimasu!
ごちそう:feast/treating (someone)|to treat (someone, e.g. to a meal)
ごちそうさまでした
It was delicious.
フゥー
苦手[にがて]:poor (at)/weak (in)|dislike (of)
ねえ ヤサコは
なんでメガばあ苦手なの？
Yasako, why don't you get along well with Mega-baa?
お年玉[おとしだま]:New Year's gift (usu. money given to a child by relatives and visitors), すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 額[がく]:picture (framed)|amount or sum (of money), 額[ひたい]:forehead/brow
８つのとき
お年玉くれたの すごい額
When I was eight, she gave me an otoshidama.
An otoshidama is a present given to kids on New Year's day.
It was a really expensive one.
それで？
And then?
花札[はなふだ]:hanafuda/Japanese playing cards (12 suits of 4 cards, each suit representing a month indicated by a flower), 倍額[ばいがく]:double amount, 巻き上げる[まきあげる]:to roll up|to take away|to blow up (dust)
そのすぐあと 花札やろうって
倍額 巻き上げられたわ
Then she said, "Let's play hanafuda."
Hanafuda is a Japanese card game.
In the end, she took twice the present's worth from me.
らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
メガばあらしいわ
Typical of Mega-baa.
練る[ねる]:to knead|to polish (a plan, etc.)|to train||, 腕[うで]:arm|skill/efforts, 腕[かいな]:arm (esp. upper arm)|counter used to measure the thickness of round objects, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
でも メタバグ練る腕は
すごくいいのよ
But she's great at kneading metabugs.
メタバグを？
Metabugs?
キレイ:pretty/lovely/beautiful
（フミエ）キレイでしょ？
It's beautiful, isn't it?
バグる:to behave buggily (software)/to act up/to behave strangely, 一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
（ヤサコ）
メタバグって 一体なんなの？
What exactly is a metabug?
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 貼り付ける[はりつける]:to paste/to stick|to station, メタタグ:META tag, 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|
さっきデンスケに貼り付けた
メタタグ覚えてる？
Do you remember the metatag I slapped on Densuke earlier?
Yeah.
原料[げんりょう]:raw materials
あれの原料なの
It's the raw material for that.
普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train, ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, マトン:mutton, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 壊す[こわす]:to break|to wreck|to break (a bill, etc.)
普通のバグは
ただペットマトンや空間を壊すだけ
Normal bugs usually damage petmatons or the Space.
偶然[ぐうぜん]:coincidence|by chance|contingency (philosophy), 役に立つ[やくにたつ]:to be helpful/to be useful, 機能[きのう]:function/facility/faculty, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
でも偶然
役に立つ機能を持ったバグ
But this bug is useful for some reason.
それがメタバグよ
That's what a metabug is.
へえー
金沢では こんなの見たことないわ
I've never seen anything like this in Kanazawa.
大黒[だいこく]:god of wealth|monk's wife, 市[いち]:market/fair, 市[し]:city, 特産品[とくさんひん]:special product, 取れる[とれる]:to come off|(of pain, a fever, etc.) to disappear|to be caught||
（フミエ）大黒市の特産品
なぜか ここでしか取れないの
It's a special product of Daikoku City.
I don't know why, but you can only get it here.
そうなんだ
Is that so?
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 片っ端[かたっぱし]:one edge/one end/one side, 消去[しょうきょ]:elimination/erasure/dying out
（フミエ）
でも最近 あのサッチーが
片っ端から消去しちゃって
But that Satchii
has been killing them off recently.
メタバグが どこで
どうやってできるのか―
Nobody knows where the metabug comes from or how it comes to be,
誰も知らないから
近頃[ちかごろ]:lately/recently/nowadays, 値段[ねだん]:price/cost, 上がる[あがる]:to rise|to enter (esp. from outdoors)|to enter (a school)||
近頃 値段が上がってるのよ
so their price is on the rise these days.
（デンスケ）ク～ン…
Downloading System Restore
Insufficient Disc Space.
Stop the Download?
ヤダ 何これ？
Oh no! What's this?
止まる[とまる]:to stop (moving)|to stop (doing, working, being supplied)|to alight, 止まる[とどまる]:to remain/to abide|to be limited to
止まらないわ
It's not stopping.
（デンスケ）ク～ン ク～ン…
ど… どうなの？
H-How is he?
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
（ヤサコ）それ 一体 何？
What on earth is that?
It's just as I thought,
やっぱり:too/also|still, イリーガル:illegal, 感染[かんせん]:infection/contagion
やっぱり イリーガルに感染してる
he's been infected by an Illegal.
イリーガル:illegal
イリーガル？
An Illegal?
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 生き物[いきもの]:living thing/animal
あなたが見たっていう
黒い生き物よ
The black thing you said you spotted.
ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, マトン:mutton, 寄生[きせい]:parasitism/parasitic, コンピューターウイルス:computer virus
ペットマトンに寄生する
コンピューターウイルスなの
It's a parasitic computer virus that lives at the expense of a petmaton.
ウイルス:virus, 大きさ[おおきさ]:size/dimensions/volume
ウイルスって大きさじゃなかったわ
It was too big to be a virus...
巨大[きょだい]:huge/gigantic/enormous, 化[か]:action of making something/-ification, ウイルス:virus, イリーガル:illegal
巨大化したウイルスなのよ
それがイリーガル
It was a magnified form of a virus.
That's an Illegal.
詳しい[くわしい]:detailed/full|knowing very well, ほとんど:mostly/nearly/practically
詳しいことは
ほとんど分かってないの
There's very little information about it.
初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
私も見るのは初めてよ
This is the first time I've seen one, too.
進化[しんか]:evolution/progress
（フミエ）バグが進化したものとも
It's said to be an evolution of a bug,
謎[なぞ]:riddle/puzzle|enigmatic, ハッカー:hacker, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
謎のハッカーが作ったものとも
言われてるけど
or something created by a mysterious hacker.
正体[しょうたい]:true character/true form|consciousness
正体は誰も知らないの
But nobody really knows what it is.
感染[かんせん]:infection/contagion, ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, 徐々[じょじょ]:gradually/steadily|soon, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 蝕む[むしばむ]:to be worm-eaten/to be eaten by worms|to affect adversely, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
感染したペットは
徐々に体を蝕(むしば)まれてしまうそうよ
I heard that the infected pets
were all eaten away, little by little.
イリーガル:illegal, 侵入[しんにゅう]:invasion/incursion/raid, 跡[あと]:trace|site|scar, 跡[せき]:trace
（フミエ）
これはイリーガルが侵入した
跡じゃないかって言われてるもの
This is what's believed to be inside a pet after the Illegal infiltrates it.
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 分離[ぶんり]:separation/partition/detachment
早く分離しないと
If it's not removed soon...
Does the host die?
死ぬの？
It doesn't say here whether it dies or not.
書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw
（フミエ）
死ぬかどうかは書いてないわ
ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET
ペットは？
このあと どうなったの？
What happened to that pet then?
よく分からない
It isn't clear.
薬[くすり]:medicine|efficacious chemical (gunpowder, pesticide, etc.)|(pottery) glaze|, 薬[やく]:dope/narcotics|medication, 練る[ねる]:to knead|to polish (a plan, etc.)|to train||
（メガばあ）薬 練ってやるぞ
I'll apply a medicine on 'im.
ダウンロード:download
（メガばあ）これは どこからか
何かをダウンロードしておる
It's downloadin' sumthin' from somewhere...
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
それは分かってるわ
一体 どこから何を？
I know that.
But what? And from where?
どこからか何かをじゃ
I have no idea.
頼りになる[たよりになる]:to be reliable
頼りにならないなあ
You're no help.
You fool!
ダウンロード:download
バカ者！
これはただのダウンロードではない
This ain't a common download!
目方[めかた]:weight, 増やす[ふやす]:to increase/to add to/to augment, 勝手に[かってに]:arbitrarily/of its own accord/voluntarily, ダウンロード:download
デンスケの目方を増やして
勝手にダウンロードしておるのじゃ
It's downloadin' on its own while Densuke's weight is increasin'.
（ヤサコ）えっ？
（フミエ）なんですって？
What?!
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, ページ:page
（フミエ）そういえば
さっきのページにあったわ
Now that you mention it, that page said
ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, 成長[せいちょう]:growth/grow to adulthood, タイプ:type/kind/sort
“ペットの中で
成長するタイプのやつがいる”って
that there are things that grow inside the pet.
ど… どうしよう
What can we do?
ダウンロード:download, 止める[とめる]:to stop|to park|to prevent||, 止める[やめる]:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel
まずは
ダウンロードを止めることじゃ！
First of all, we got to stop the download.
おばば なんとかできるの？
Can you do that, Granny?
任せる[まかせる]:to entrust (e.g. a task) to another|to passively leave to someone else's facilities|to leave to take its natural course||
わしに任せるのじゃ
Leave it to me.
（ヤサコ）ちょっと おばば
Hey, Granny...
What are you doing?
拝む[おがむ]:to assume the posture of praying|to beg|to see (something or someone of high status), 場合[ばあい]:case/situation
何してるの？　拝んでる場合じゃ…
This isn't the time to be praying!
焦る[あせる]:to be in a hurry/to be impatient/to be flustered
そう 焦るでない
（鈴(りん)の音）
Don't be so impatient.
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 工房[こうぼう]:workshop/studio/atelier, ようこそ:welcome!/nice to see you!
わしの電脳工房に ようこそじゃ
Welcome to my cyberstudio.
Where did you steal all this from?
盗む[ぬすむ]:to steal
こんなの どこから盗んできたの？
プログラム:program/programme
わしがプログラムしたのじゃ
I programmed it myself.
へえー
読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess
（メガばあ）
まず メタバグの目を読むのじゃ
Now we have to read into the eye of the metabug.
（ヤサコ）
そうすると どうなるの？
What for?
個[こ, コ]:counter for articles|counter for military units|individual, 個[か, カ]:counter for the ichi-ni-san counting system (usu. directly preceding the item being counted)/a noun read using its on-yomi, 役[えき, えだち]:war/campaign|unpaid work (ritsuryo system), 役[やく]:use|post|scoring combination (e.g. in mahjong, card games, etc.), 立つ[たつ]:to stand|to find oneself (e.g. in a difficult position)|to depart (on a plane, train, etc.)
メタバグは１個ずつでは
なんの役にも立たんじゃがな
A metabug alone is useless.
But when you put two of them together...
つなぎ合わせる[つなぎあわせる]:to connect/to join/to join or tie or knot together
つなぎ合わせると…
Amazing!
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
（ヤサコ）すごい！
読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess, 方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||, 入れる[いれる]:to put in|to admit|to accept||, 精進[しょうじん, そうじん]:concentration|asceticism|adherence to a vegetarian diet, たまもの:gift/boon|(good) result
目の読み方 力の入れ方
どれも精進のたまものじゃ
Both the reading of its eye and their kneading are the fruits of mastery.
The only one able to do it is Mega-baa.
並[なみ]:average|line|mid-grade|
これができるのはメガばあだけよ
並のばあさんじゃないのよ
She's not your average granny.
Bite your tongue.
余計[よけい]:too many|unnecessary|abundantly
余計なことを言うでない
メタタグ:META tag, 加工[かこう]:manufacturing/processing/treatment
さっ あとは
これをメタタグに加工すれば…
So now we have to transform it into a metatag.
ふんっ！
Done.
出来上がる[できあがる]:to be completed/to be finished|to be very drunk
出来上がりじゃ
So that's how you make metatags.
メタタグ:META tag, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
メタタグって こうやって作るんだ
Cyberinsecticide!
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 虫下し[むしくだし]:deworming medicine
電脳虫下し～！
An insecticide?
虫下し[むしくだし]:deworming medicine, ワクチン:vaccine, ソフト:soft
（ヤサコ）虫下し？
（フミエ）ワクチンソフトのことよ
A vaccination program.
For dangerous insects you use an insecticide,
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 虫[むし]:insect/bug/cricket, 虫下し[むしくだし]:deworming medicine
（メガばあ）悪い虫には虫下し
so for computer viruses you use a vaccination program.
コンピューターウイルス:computer virus, ワクチン:vaccine, ソフト:soft
コンピューターウイルスには
ワクチンソフト
That's great news!
治る[なおる]:to be cured/to get well|to get mended
よかった！
じゃあデンスケ治るのね
So Densuke will recover!
I'd do anything for my beloved granddaughter...
可愛い[かわいい, かわゆい]:cute|dear|cute little, 孫[まご]:grandchild
（メガばあ）可愛い孫のためじゃ
Thank you so much, Granny!
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
おばあちゃん ありがとう
...on one condition.
代わり[かわり]:substitute|stand-in|compensation||, 代わり[がわり]:substitute for ..., 条件[じょうけん]:condition/conditions/term
その代わり条件がある
Wh-What's with this eight?
番[ばん]:number (in a series)|(one's) turn|watch|, 番[つがい]:(one) pair (e.g. of birds)/brace|joint
何？　何？　８番って何？
It's your membership number in my investigation agency.
我が[わが]:my/our/one's own, 探偵[たんてい]:detective/sleuth/investigator, 事務所[じむしょ]:office, 会員[かいいん]:member/the membership, ナンバー:number
我が探偵事務所の会員ナンバーじゃ
What's that supposed to mean?
どういう:somehow/how/in what way
どういうことよ
I'll apply this medicine for free,
薬[くすり]:medicine|efficacious chemical (gunpowder, pesticide, etc.)|(pottery) glaze|, 薬[やく]:dope/narcotics|medication, 練る[ねる]:to knead|to polish (a plan, etc.)|to train||, 代わり[かわり]:substitute|stand-in|compensation||, 代わり[がわり]:substitute for ..., 会員[かいいん]:member/the membership
薬はタダで練ってやる
その代わり会員になるのじゃ
but in exchange,
you'll join my agency.
Mega-baa always increases the membership like this.
会員[かいいん]:member/the membership, 増やす[ふやす]:to increase/to add to/to augment
メガばあ いつも
この手で 会員 増やすのよ
She grabs a hold of your weak point and then offers you a solution.
弱み[よわみ]:(a) weakness/shortcoming/failing, 握る[にぎる]:to clasp|to make (nigirizushi, rice ball, etc.)|to seize (power, etc.), 持ちかける[もちかける]:to offer (a suggestion, etc.)/to propose (an idea, etc.)/to approach with (a proposal, etc.)
弱みを握って持ちかけるの
Why?
何よ それ
But once you join, you'll see it's really fun!
結構[けっこう]:splendid|sufficient|well enough||, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
でも入ってみると
結構 楽しいわよ
C'mon, join us!
ねっ 入りましょ
しかたない:it can't be helped/it's inevitable/it's no use
うん… しかたないな
Well, if I really have to...
I'm Number Seven.
番[ばん]:number (in a series)|(one's) turn|watch|, 番[つがい]:(one) pair (e.g. of birds)/brace|joint, よろしく:well/properly|best regards
私は７番よ　これからよろしくね
Nice to meet you!
I'm Number Zero.
番[ばん]:number (in a series)|(one's) turn|watch|, 番[つがい]:(one) pair (e.g. of birds)/brace|joint
私はゼロ番よ
Pleased to meet you.
よろしく:well/properly|best regards
これからよろしくねじゃ ヘヘッ
Yasako.
ヤサコ
Welcome to the Coil Cyberinvestigation Agency!
コイル:coil, 探偵[たんてい]:detective/sleuth/investigator, 局[きょく]:bureau|office (e.g. post, telephone)|affair|, 局[つぼね]:court lady|separate room in a palace (esp. for a lady) (Heian period)|room for a very low class prostitute|, ようこそ:welcome!/nice to see you!
コイル探偵局に ようこそ！
（ヤサコ）あっ！
（フミエ）何？　どうしたの？
What's wrong?
分離[ぶんり]:separation/partition/detachment, 黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 飛び出す[とびだす]:to jump out|to appear (suddenly)|to protrude|
だって分離したら あの黒いのが
飛び出してくるんでしょ？
If we remove that black thing, it'll burst in here!
解析[かいせき]:analysis/analytical study|parsing, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, かかる:to span/to bridge/to cross, かかる:to take (a resource, e.g. time or money)|to hang
大丈夫よ
この分だと解析に明日までかかるわ
Don't worry.
At this rate, it'll take till tomorrow to complete the analysis.
分離[ぶんり]:separation/partition/detachment, 始まる[はじまる]:to begin|to happen (again)|to date (from)
分離が始まるのは そのあと
The quarantine will start once that is done.
そうなんだ
Is that so?
私たち[わたしたち, わたくしたち]:we/us, 攻撃[こうげき]:attack/strike|criticism
私たちは
サッチーに攻撃されても
If we're shot by Satchii,
データ:data/datum, 飛ぶ[とぶ]:to fly/to soar|to jump, 死[し]:death|death penalty (by strangulation or decapitation)|(an) out, にゃあ:mewing (cat)/meow/miaow
データが飛ぶだけで
死にゃあしないけど
all we lose is our data, but we won't die.
自衛[じえい]:self-defense/self-defence, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
自衛のために
メガビーは持ってたほうがいいわ
But for self-defense, you'd better have a mega-be with you.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, ビーム:beam
えっ メガビーって
さっきのビーム？
By mega-be, do you mean the mega-beam
you mentioned earlier?
私 ああいうのは ちょっと…
I'm not really...
いいから いいから
Just take it.
データ:data/datum, 修復[しゅうふく, しゅふく]:restoration/repair/mending, お年玉[おとしだま]:New Year's gift (usu. money given to a child by relatives and visitors), 換算[かんさん, かんざん]:conversion (e.g. yen to dollars)/change/exchange, かかる:to span/to bridge/to cross, かかる:to take (a resource, e.g. time or money)|to hang
データの修復は お年玉換算で
２年分もかかっちゃうのよ
Recovering the lost data would cost the equivalent of two year's otoshidama.
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
（フミエ）じゃ 何かあったら
すぐ電話してね
Okay, so give me a call if anything happens.
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
（ヤサコ）ありがとう
Thank you!
やっと:at last/at length|barely, 見つける[みつける, みっける]:to discover|to locate|to be used to seeing
やっと見つけたわ
I finally found her.
えーっと:let me see/well/errr ..., タオル:towel, パジャマ:pajamas/pyjamas
（ヤサコ）
えーっと… タオルとパジャマ
The towel, pyjamas...
あっ これは…
This is...
懐かしい[なつかしい]:dear/desired/missed
うわっ 懐かしい！
This was such a long time ago!
I'm so bad at writing.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 字[あざ]:section of village, 字[じ]:character (i.e. kanji)|hand-writing|the ... word (i.e. "the L word" - "love"), 下手[したて, したで]:humble position/inferior|underarm grip on opponent's belt, 下手[しもて]:lower part/foot|left part of the stage (audience's or camera's POV)
私 すごく 字 下手
“４４２３”？
4-4-2-3?
（ヤサコ）
４４２３ってなんだろう？
What could 4-4-2-3 be?
４月23日ってことかな？
Maybe April 23rd...
大事[だいじ, おおごと]:important/valuable|safe (Tochigi dialect), 忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of
なんか大事なこと忘れてる
I feel like I'm forgetting something important...
なんだっけ？
What could it be?
ただいま:Here I am/I'm home!|presently
（一郎(いちろう)）ただいま
I'm back.
お父さん[おとうさん, おとっさん]:father/dad/papa, おかえり:return|welcome home
あっ お父さん おかえり
Welcome home, Dad.
ダンボール:(corrugated) cardboard, 片づく[かたづく]:to be put in order|to be disposed of|to be finished|
（一郎）ダンボール片づいたか？
（ヤサコ）まだ
Did you get the boxes in order?
Not yet.
どうせ:anyhow/in any case|at best, 昔[むかし]:olden days/former, アルバム:album, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess, じゃう:to do something completely
フッ どうせ昔のアルバムかなんか
読んじゃったんだろ？
Still, you read all those illustrated books.
Yeah...
まあね
お父さん[おとうさん, おとっさん]:father/dad/papa, 何回[なんかい]:how many times?
ねえ お父さん
私 こっちに来たの何回目だっけ？
Hey, Dad...
How many times have I come here?
うーん:hmm/well, 回[かい]:counter for occurrences|a time|inning (baseball)||
（一郎）うーん… ３回目だな
This should be the third time.
お店[おたな]:merchant's home (esp. used by apprentices, etc.)|(your) rental home, 初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
おばあちゃんのお店 見るの
今日が初めてか
So today is the first time you've seen Granny's store?
I didn't know.
ビックリ:to be surprised/to be amazed/to be frightened
ビックリしたろ？
駄菓子[だがし]:cheap sweets, 屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
なんで駄菓子屋って
教えてくれなかったの？
Why didn't you tell me it's a dagashi store?
恥[はじ, じょく]:shame/embarrassment/disgrace
恥かいちゃったよ
I was so embarrassed.
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
（一郎）ハッハハハ
おばあちゃんの話すると―
Granny said
耳[みみ]:ear|hearing|edge|, いでる:to go/to come
いっつも耳塞いでたのは
優子じゃないか
you were plugging your ears!
裸になる[はだかになる]:to take off one's clothes/to undress
ヤ… ヤダ！
何 裸になってんのよ！
Hey!
Why are you naked?!
娘[じょう]:unmarried woman|Miss|-ess, 娘[むすめ]:(my) daughter|girl (i.e. a young, unmarried woman)
娘の前で！
And in front of your own daughter!
（一郎）アイタタタ…
Ouch!
裸になる[はだかになる]:to take off one's clothes/to undress, 風呂[ふろ]:bath|bathroom|room for drying lacquerware|, 入れる[いれる]:to put in|to admit|to accept||
は… 裸になんなきゃ
風呂に入れないだろ
How am I supposed to take a bath with my clothes on?
まったく:really/truly|indeed
まったくもう…
Geez!
あっ そうだ
Oh, that's right.
昔[むかし]:olden days/former
ねえ 昔 こっちに来たときって
おじじの…
Say, that time when we came here some time ago for Grandpa's...
亡くなる[なくなる]:to die
（一郎）そう
おじいちゃんが亡くなったとき
Yeah, when Grandpa died.
迷子になる[まいごになる]:to get lost/to become lost/to go astray
そのとき 私
迷子にならなかった？
Did I get lost that time by any chance?
覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|
（一郎）ああ なった なった
よく覚えてんな
Ah, yes, you did!
You remember!
変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
私 なんか
変なこと言ってなかった？
Did I say anything strange?
鍵穴[かぎあな, カギあな]:keyhole
鍵穴とか
Something about a keyhole...
（一郎）さあ どうだったかな？
Who knows?
頃[ころ, ごろ]:(approximate) time|suitable time (or condition)|time of year, 頃[けい]:qing (Chinese unit of land area equal to 100 mu), 変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
お前 あの頃
いっつも変なこと言ってたし
You used to say a lot of strange things back then.
どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.)
どんな？
Like what?
指さす[ゆびさす]:to point at
（一郎）なんでも指さしては
“ウンチ！”って
You kept pointing at things and repeating "poop".
（ヤサコ）
デンスケも もう年だよな
Densuke has grown big...
えらい:great/excellent|awful, 目に遭う[めにあう]:to go through/to suffer/to experience (something unpleasant)
今日もえらい目に遭わせちゃって
ごめんね
I'm sorry for getting you in trouble today.
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, 触る[さわる]:to touch/to feel, 感触[かんしょく]:feel (i.e. tactile sensation)/touch/feeling
電脳ペットにも
触った感触があればいいのにな
I wish I knew what a cyberpet feels like.
フカフカなのかな？
You must be so soft and fluffy...
壊れる[こわれる]:to be broken/to break|to fall through, 痛い[いたい]:painful/sore|exceeding, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET
壊れたら痛いのかな？
電脳ペットも
I wonder if a cyberpet would suffer,
if it broke down.
小さい[ちいさい]:small/little/tiny, 頃[ころ, ごろ]:(approximate) time|suitable time (or condition)|time of year, 頃[けい]:qing (Chinese unit of land area equal to 100 mu), なめる:to lick|to taste, なめる:to be slippery/to be slimy|to behave charmingly
小さい頃
デンスケがなめてくれたら
I remember one time when I was little, Densuke licked a wound I had,
不思議[ふしぎ]:wonder/miracle/strange, 痛み[いたみ]:pain/ache|damage, 消える[きえる]:to go out/to vanish/to disappear
不思議と痛みが消えたな
and the pain mysteriously disappeared.
そうだ デンスケ
That's right, Densuke.
お世話になる[おせわになる]:to receive favor (favour)/to be much obliged to someone/to be indebted, お礼[おれい, おんれい]:thanks|manners|bow||, 魔法[まほう]:magic/witchcraft/sorcery, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse), あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
京子がお世話になったお礼に
私が魔法かけてあげる
To thank you for taking care of Kyoko,
I'll cast a magic spell on you.
痛い[いたい]:painful/sore|exceeding, 飛ぶ[とぶ]:to fly/to soar|to jump
痛いの痛いの飛んでけ～！
Pain, pain,
go away!
Disconnecting from link
Connected to C Domain
（少年）ユウコ ユウコ…
Yuko...
Yuko!
誰？
Who are you?
聞こえる[きこえる]:to be heard/to be audible|to be said to be
（少年）僕だ 聞こえているか？
It's me...
Can't you hear me?
鍵[かぎ, カギ]:key|lock, 鍵[けん]:key (of a piano, etc.), 開ける[あける]:to open (a door, etc.)|to open (for business, etc.)|to empty||, 開ける[ひらける]:to become opened up|to develop|to be enlightened
鍵を… 鍵を開けてはならない
You must not...
You must not open the door.
近づく[ちかづく, ちかずく]:to approach/to draw near|to get acquainted with
あれに近づいてはならない
You must not...
Get close to that.
誰？　誰なの？
Who...?
Who are you?
（少年）僕は ４４２３
I am...
4-4-2-3.
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister
君のお兄ちゃんだ
Your brother...
ハァ…
お父さん[おとうさん, おとっさん]:father/dad/papa
（静江）お父さん 時間 時間！
（一郎）んっ？
Honey, it's time!
いじめ:bullying/teasing
いじめちゃダメよ
Leave him alone.
ウン… チ！
Okay.
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
お兄ちゃんなんて
いないんだけどなあ…
But I don't have a brother...
頼む[たのむ]:to request|to call|to entrust to|
（静江）じゃあ 京子 頼みましたよ
Take care of Kyoko.
（静江）
おばあちゃん 大丈夫かな？
I wonder if Granny will be alright.
（モジョ）モジョ
（モジョ）モジョ モジョ
よいしょ:(expression of) effort or strain/Yo-heave-ho!|to butter up
（デンスケの鳴き声）
（京子）よいしょ…
（京子）うむっ これはヒドい！
すぐにオペだ！
This is awful!
You need an operation.
赤[あか]:red|red-containing colour (e.g. brown, pink, orange)|Red (i.e. communist)||
赤！
Red!
赤[あか]:red|red-containing colour (e.g. brown, pink, orange)|Red (i.e. communist)||
赤！
Red.
黄色[きいろ, こうしょく]:yellow/amber
（京子）黄色！
Yellow!
黄色[きいろ, こうしょく]:yellow/amber
黄色！
Yellow.
これはヒドい…
This is really bad...
ただいま:Here I am/I'm home!|presently
（ヤサコ）ただいま
I'm back.
Here you go, Dear.
ご飯[ごはん]:cooked rice|meal
はい あなた ご飯よ
Your meal.
粘土[ねんど, ねばつち]:clay, 食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off
あなた 私の粘土が
食べられないっていうの？
Dear,
are you saying that you can't eat my clay?
You're so mean!
罰を与える[ばつをあたえる]:to punish (e.g. a child, etc.)
ヒドいわ 罰を与える！
Serves you right!
ああ～ ウンチ！
Poop!
おしっこ:wee-wee/pee-pee/number one
おしっこ～！
Gotta pee!
（モジョたち）
モジョ モジョ モジョ…
（京子）ヒヒッ ニェヘヘ～
（モジョたち）
モジョ モジョ モジョ…
Downloading System Restore
Packet Fee
モジョ！
Fiends!
曲者[くせもの]:ruffian|peculiar person|tricky thing||
曲者！
（モジョたち）モジョー！
モジョ モジョ モジョ…
Time to pay!
成敗[せいばい]:punishment/judgement/judgment, 成敗[せいはい]:success and failure
成敗！
（モジョたち）モジョー！
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
ヘッヘヘ…
悪(わり)い子はいねえが～？
Now where have all the bad guys run off to?
Preview
Next time on Dennou Coil.
Yuko and Yuko
See you next time!
次回[じかい]:next time (occasion), 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, コイル:coil
（ヤサコ）
次回 「電脳コイル」
〝優子と勇子(ゆうこ) 〞
楽しみ[たのしみ]:enjoyment/pleasure|anticipation
お楽しみに